<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[RubyNepal]]></title>
  <link href="http://RubyNepal.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://RubyNepal.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-29T15:29:56+05:45</updated>
  <id>http://RubyNepal.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[RubyNepal]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monthly Dev Meetup July 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://RubyNepal.github.io/blog/2014/07/31/dev-meetup-july-26-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T19:37:00+05:45</updated>
    <id>http://RubyNepal.github.io/blog/2014/07/31/dev-meetup-july-26-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The tech scene in Kathmandu is ever growing but it is rather lacking a sense of community. Dev Meetup aims to fill this void with a regular meetup for developers where like minded individuals can gather, get to know each other and share their ideas/views.</p>

<p>The meetup will be carried out monthly (last Saturday of the month) to cover web development topics like &lsquo;ruby&rsquo;, &lsquo;rails&rsquo;, &lsquo;javascript&rsquo;, &lsquo;devops&rsquo;, &lsquo;databases&rsquo;, etc.</p>

<p>The first successful <a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/768447783198796/">Dev Meetup</a> was held on July 26, 2014 at CloudFactory, the next Dev Meetup is scheduled for August 30th, 2014 at the same venue.</p>

<p>Sign up at <a href="https://plus.google.com/events/cr78vpsi1466vv0ldj990fdgdr8">https://plus.google.com/events/cr78vpsi1466vv0ldj990fdgdr8</a> to join us. Kudos to CloudFactory for sponsoring both the events.</p>

<p>Follow us <a href="http://twitter.com/ruby_nepal">@ruby_nepal</a> for latest updates and news.</p>

<p>If you are not sure what to expect or missed the 1st Dev Meetup, check out the pics and videos from the first one.</p>

<p><strong> Pictures </strong></p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BtdOPL3CMAAlPlN.jpg">
<img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BtdmzUJCUAEDi0W.jpg"></p>

<p><strong> FB Event Pics and Details: </strong>
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/768447783198796/">https://www.facebook.com/events/768447783198796/</a></p>

<p><strong> Videos And Slides:  </strong></p>

<p><em>I) 10 Ways We Can Be Better by Mark Sears</em> &ndash; <a href="http://twitter.com/marktsears">@marktsears</a></p>

<p><img src="https://d3j5vwomefv46c.cloudfront.net/photos/large/861728292.jpg?1406529728"></p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/COBCnZls5rE" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<p><a href="http://bit.ly/ktmdevmeetup">Slides &ndash; Mark DevMeetup Talk</a></p>

<p><em>II) Ansible by Bikash Kaji Basukala</em> &ndash; <a href="http://twitter.com/kajisaap">@kajisaap</a></p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BtdXoatCcAAmTPB.jpg"></p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZKoSG8bxw0A" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<p><a href="https://bit.ly/kajionansible">Slides &ndash; Kaji DevMeetup Talk</a></p>

<p><em>III) Ember.js with Ember-Cli by Sachin Sagar Rai</em> &ndash; <a href="http://twitter.com/millisami">@millisami</a></p>

<p><img src="https://d3j5vwomefv46c.cloudfront.net/photos/large/861727487.png?1406528902"></p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Z_HCTb5I1lM" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<p><a href="http://nepalonrails.com/blog/2014/07/emberjs-app-using-ember-cli/">Slides &ndash; Millisami DevMeetup Talk</a></p>

<p>If you want to be a speaker in future meetups or wish someone would impart the knowledge or have any  suggestions, then do let us know. If you want to host / sponser the event at your company then ping <a href="http://twitter.com/zoraslapen">@zoraslapen</a>.</p>

<p>Looking forward to meet you guys!</p>

<blockquote><p>Saroj Maharjan &ndash; <a href="http://github.com/zoras">zoras</a></p>

<p>Organiser, Dev Meetup</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails MeetUp Kathmandu 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://RubyNepal.github.io/blog/2013/06/12/rails-meetup-kathmandu-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-12T23:19:00+05:45</updated>
    <id>http://RubyNepal.github.io/blog/2013/06/12/rails-meetup-kathmandu-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every year around the world there are ruby meetup and rails meetup happenings, so why not organise the first ever Rails MeetUp here at Kathmandu. This meetup will not be just an event but also be a point of unite and interaction and sharing of knowledge and experiences between the distributed ruby developers in kathmandu valley.</p>

<p>This event we are planning to schedule is around in the end of July 2013, however all the plans are not decided, talks are going on.
We want a lot of people and groups to be engaged to make this event success. Feel free to suggest us ideas and to come up forward.</p>

<p>And if you want to present or be a speaker at the meetup , you are most welcome and this is your time to send us details.</p>

<p>Thought about speaking? Want to give speaking at Rails Meetup a shot, but not sure what to talk about?</p>

<p>Even if you have a tiny inkling that you&rsquo;d want to speak, like your experience, technology, tips and tricks, even may be a tutorial, we&rsquo;ll help you to ideate, write, and present.</p>

<p>Great business starts with unsurpassed people skills, it is a great oppurtunity for tech business houses to be promoted and find connections at the event. We welcome sponshorship of any kind financial, promotional, resources or even may be a service or server.</p>

<h3>Contact Points are:</h3>

<p><a href="mailto:millisami@gmail.com">Sachin Sagar Rai</a></p>

<p><a href="mailto:dipil.saud@gmail.com">Dipil Saud</a></p>

<p><a href="mailto:sawrows@gmail.com">Saroj Maharjan</a></p>

<p><a href="mailto:shrey.is.shrey@gmail.com">Shrey Ghimire</a></p>

<p><a href="mailto:poisonta03@gmail.com">Ashis Bista</a></p>

<p>We will be posting dates, venue and schedules.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby on Rails Training at Hetauda School Of Management]]></title>
    <link href="http://RubyNepal.github.io/blog/2013/06/12/ror-trainings-at-hetauda-school-of-management/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-12T22:47:00+05:45</updated>
    <id>http://RubyNepal.github.io/blog/2013/06/12/ror-trainings-at-hetauda-school-of-management</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are organising 4 sessions(one session per 2 week) ruby on rails training series at Hetauta School of Management for BIM final year students from May 25, 2013. We recieved an special invitation from the college to do this training ans we are pleased to aid the college for conducting such extra curricular programs that will help students to broaded their skills and also we are happy to spread the ruby and ruby on rails wisedom to our next-generation IT professionals.</p>

<p>Our training structure is designed as shown below:</p>

<ul>
<li>[May 25] Front-End Web Basics (HTML5/CSS3, Javascript/JQuery, AJAX, JSON)</li>
<li>[June 8] Ruby Literacy session (Ruby Installation and Ruby Basics, irb, OOP and Ruby, Modules and File Operations, Blocks )</li>
<li>[June 22] Getting started with Rails (RubyGems, Rails Installation, Rails Basics)</li>
<li>[July 6] Up with Rails ( Advance Rails, debugging, deloyment with heroku, Project)</li>
</ul>


<p>if you are around Hetauda, You can catch us at Hetauda School Of Management.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we build rubynepal using Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://RubyNepal.github.io/blog/2013/06/06/how-we-build-rubynepal-using-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-06T19:18:00+05:45</updated>
    <id>http://RubyNepal.github.io/blog/2013/06/06/how-we-build-rubynepal-using-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is not another getting started with octopress guide, this is sharing of our experience and couple of hacks we did while developing rubynepal, that may be helpful to others.</p>

<p>In the beginning of June 2013, We came up with this idea of building a community website for ruby developers of nepal.
We didn&rsquo;t need to have a full content management features but we needed features like blog support, pages support, ease for deployments and easy contributing mechanism. Finally, we decided to build rubynepal.org with <a href="http://octopress.org">octopress</a> and github pages. With this we could to tap out Markdown without needing a web-based WYSIWYG editor and type a command to send everything up to the free Github Pages service and our whole website would be a github repo, perfect for collaboration.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/">docs</a> has pretty neat documentation for installing octopress, configuring setting up github pages. Within few minutes basic website was up at github pages.</p>

<p>Next, themes, we forked this beautiful and responsive theme <a href="https://github.com/shashankmehta/greyshade">greyshade</a> and customized it. Upto here we had a basic rubynepal.org up and running.</p>

<p>Now, octopress has its root path that displays the posts ie. essentially blog index, but we needed to have a page instead of blog index.
For this, first we moved <em>source/index.html</em> to <em>source/blog/index.html</em>. Then, created a markdown where we wrote what is to be there in homepage.
We put all such kinds of markdown inside <em>_partial</em> folder.
Then, in <em>source/index.html</em> we got rid of all exsiting code with</p>

<figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='html'><span class='line'>  ---
</span><span class='line'>  layout: default
</span><span class='line'>  ---
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;div</span> <span class="na">id=</span><span class="s">&quot;page_about&quot;</span><span class="nt">/&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    {% render_partial _partial/about.markdown %}
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;/div&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This way about.markdown will be rendered in root page while blog index will be available at <em>/blog</em>.</p>

<p>Now we had to put a list of developers and advisors info in members page. One way was to dump those info to a yml file and access data from there. Matt Swanson has excellent write on how to do that in his <a href="http://mdswanson.com/blog/2013/06/03/jekyll-201.html">blog</a>. With this, we could dump the data from yml file to jekyll <em>site</em> variable.</p>

<p>Finally, we built a small heroku app that powers the join page forms and we have rubynepal.org as how it is now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
